So today we will compare two plans, that
is HDFC Ergo Optima Secure and Aditya
Birla Activ Max.  So
we will see what are the differences and
similarities in these two plans and in the end we are also going to compare the premiums.
[Music]
So quick reminder before we start the video,
if you haven't already, please subscribe to our channel.
So that you
get the right infection at the right time.  So
first we will talk about the USP of the product.   The
USP of HDFC Ergo Optima Secure is
its Secure Benefit which is two
times three times cover from day one.  If
you are taking a policy of Rs 10 lakh then
from the first day you will be covered for Rs 20 lakh or Rs 30 lakh.  The
USP of Aditya Birla Activ Max
is Super Credit which means your sum
assured will go up to 500%.  100% will keep
increasing every year and will go up to a maximum of 500%.  There are
many
good riders available in both the plans which you
can choose as per your need, we will
see them in the end.  Now let's talk
about room rent eligibility.  There is
no capping in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.
You can opt for any room and actual pay will be made on S.  There
is no capping in Aditya Activan also.  You
can take any room.  And here if you
want to take the room modifier rider, it will
reduce the room.  So what will happen if
you do not want any room option, you
want single room is also ok for me
or twin sharing basis room is also ok, then
your premium gets reduced, so you
can choose room modification rider. Minimum
and maximum entry age Minimum entry age
is 18 years in HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure maximum there is no limit Same
goes for Aditya Birla Activ minimum
entry age is 18 years, maximum there is no limit
Minimum sum assured is available in HDFC Ergo is
5 lpa maximum is 2 crore
Minimum sum assured is available in Aditya Birla Activ
One is 5 lpa maximum is 6 crore
Policy tenure One year, two year, three year
policy is available in both the companies.
Now let's talk about bonuses.  Plus benefit
is there in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.  Meaning
this is a loyalty bonus.  Whatever your sum
assured is, 50% of it will be
added next year as a loyalty bonus.  This
is not linked to the claim.  Irrespective of
claim.  Every year your 50-50% sum assured will
increase and be added to your policy.
In Aditya Active On Max, your sum
assured will increase by 100%.  Maximum will go up to 500%.
And will not reduce in case there are
future claims.  This is in the Active One Max.
In Vital it will go up to a maximum of 100%.
Your one year increase will be 50%.  The maximum will
go up to 100%.  Like in HDFC,
in Vital.  So let me tell you a little difference between Max and Vital.
Everyone can take Max policy.  But where you have
more comorbidities, more pre-existing
conditions, then vital goes away.  So,
Aditya Birla Active One is also available for your heart diseases.
This is a USP for you that
you will get this even in case of someone who has undergone angioplasty.  If
COPD is your pre-
existing condition then you will get Aditya Birla
Active One.  So where there
is more chronicity of illness, there it
is vital.  Suppose you have diabetes and
your HBC is very high then you will
get vital.  From HB1 itself, if your with in 8 means
under eight then you will get Aditya
Birla Active Max, there
are differences in the premium of both but Vital is for
someone who is not getting the policy, has more
chronic conditions, has more pre-
existing conditions, then they can choose Vital.
Now let's talk about day care
procedures.  Day care procedures are those that occur within
24 hours if you are being discharged.  There are
some procedures which,
due to advancement in science, do
not require you to be hospitalized for 24 hours.  Cater
Act, chemotherapy, dialysis, all these
are covered in these given policies.  Then let's
talk about Ayush hospitalization.   There
is AYUSH, Ayurveda, Yoga, Unani,
Siddha, Homeopathy, their
hospitalization is also covered
in your policies.  Refill benefit.  Refill
benefit is that if your base sum
assured and bonus are exhausted and you
need hospitalization again, then it will be
refilled.  So this is
for the next hospitalization and is triggered
after the first claim.  Refill
is available in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure once a year.
You can use it for any illness.  Beans can also cause
illness.  It can also be different.  You can use it for the same
person or for a different person.
So, to make it unlimited, you
can add Unlimited Restore Rider by paying a nominal premium.
So that it gets refilled unlimited number of times.  The
policy of Rs 10 lakh has
become Rs 1 lakh because of the secure
benefit.  You have claimed the entire amount of ₹ 20 lakh.
Now another claim has come.
Then ₹1 lakh was refilled.  Then the
claim came again and ₹1 lakh was refilled.  So
this is called Unlimited Restore Benefit.
Unlimited is also available in Aditya Active One.
Unlimited restores by
default.  Emergency Road Ambulance.
Emergency Road Ambulance has you covered.  There
is no actual limit on this.  Whatever
expenses are incurred will be paid.  Emergency Air
Ambulance is covered for Rs. 5 lakh in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.
You can add air ambulance as a rider in Aditya Birla Activan plans
if you need it.
Complimentary wellness test.
At HDFC Arko Optima Secure, you
can get a wellness test done on a reimbursement basis, which is maximum up to
₹15,000.  The amount up to which you can get reimbursed depends on your sum assured.
In Aditya Birla's plan, this is on a cashless
basis.  You
can get the test done as per their list.  Wellness benefits.  So the
wellness benefit is basically that
you are given some discounts based on your fitness activity.
This is not available in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.
Available at Aditya Birla Plus.
They are called health returns.  The more fit you
are, the more health returns you get.
Discount is available on the
renewal premium which is up to 100% in
case of Aditya Birla. Pre & Post
Hospitalization 60 Days Pre & 180 Days
Post Hospitalization Expenses are covered by
HDFC Optima Secure.   This
means that you can get reimbursement for
60 days before and
180 days after the hospitalization for which you are getting hospitalized.
In Aditya Birla Active One, you can get the expenses reimbursed for 90 days before and
180 days after.
E Consultation E Consultation
is available in HDFC and Optima Secure.
Tele Consultation is
available as an add on in Aditya Birla Active Plus.  Riders can
take e-consultation.  So e-
consultation
is available here for 51 critical illnesses.  In HDFC Aego Optima Secure.
Modern Treatments and Robotic
Surgeries.  So whatever modern
treatments are available nowadays, robotic surgeries, they are
covered in both your plans.  Up
to some assurance non payable items
are inbuilt.  Your HDFC Ergo Optima Secure
is covered.  All your non-payable items are covered.
Anescher B. on S.  Aditya Birla
's Plus has a list of 147 items.  He
is covered in both.  Consumable items.
Also in Active One Max and Active One
Bittle.  Copayment.  So there
is no co-payment option in any plan.  This is a fully payable
claim.  Deductible.  So deductible is an
option where you pay the initial amount
if any claim comes and the
insurance company pays the claims above that.
Generally it is a small amount, so
in return the insurance company gives you a discount on the premium.
So, deductible options are
available for maternity expenses in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure and
Aditya Birla Active One plans as well.
So maternity
expenses can be covered in your policy.
You
can avail Parent Hood Rider in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.  So that the
delivery cost will be covered after 2 years
and you will be given delivery coverage up to a maximum of Rs 2 lakh.
Rider is not available in Aditya Activa.  Then comes OPD.
So for OPD also rider is available in HDFC
and Optima Well Being in Optima Secure
which you can choose.
We have made a detailed video on this also.  You can refer.
So you can choose Optima Well Being
so that you can get your OPD coverage.
This is not available in Aditya Birla Activ Plus.
Global cover.  So global
cover is not available in these policies.  Here
comes another global policy from HDFC Ergo.
You can see that if you want to take global cover.
Now let's talk about waiting
periods.  So what are the waiting periods
in this policy?  The initial waiting period is
30 days.  If you talk about the waiting period of slow growing illnesses which are
stone, cataract, hernia, piles,
fibroids, knee replacement.  All these things will
not be covered for you for 2 years.  Then there is the
waiting period for pre-existing conditions.  There will be a
waiting period of three years depending on the existing conditions.  This is for
both the policies.  And here is a rider which is
called ABCD Rider
in HDFC Optima Secure.  If you already have asthma, BP,
cholesterol, diabetes then
you can choose this rider and
get your coverage in 30 days.  Aditya Birla
Active One has these riders ABCD Plus
rider which includes asthma, BP, cholesterol,
diabetes, angioplasty, obesity
and COPD.  So you can get all these things
covered from day one with Aditya Birla by
opting for this rider.
For all other conditions, there will be a waiting period of three years
for pre-existing conditions.  Now let's talk about
optional riders, which are the
riders available that you can
add to your policy.  First Rider
Unlimited Restore Rider in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure.
Meaning, if you want to multiply the restore
benefit an unlimited number of times, then you can
take the Unlimited Restore Rider.  The second benefit
available is hospital cash.  You will get this maximum of ₹2000 per day for the number of
days you are
hospitalized.  Then there
is the critical illness rider.  There
are 51 listed critical illnesses that you
can claim.  So different plans are defined.
If you have taken this rider, then if a critical illness occurs, then a one-time lump sum
payment is also made.  This means that hospitalization is
covered in your policy.  On top of that,
one time lump sum payment will also be made.  Then there is
IPA which is individual personal
accidental cover.  So here accidental
death and permanent disability are also covered
by opting for this rider.  Then there
is your Optima Well Being which is your OPD
rider that you can choose if you
need it.  Then comes ABCD Rider.
These new riders have been introduced.
We had also made a video on these new riders earlier.
You can refer that also.  If you
want to refer.  So you can get A B C D Asthma,
BP, Cholesterol, Diabetes
covered after 30 days.  Then Limitless Rider
Limitless Rider means that
whatever your claim amount is, the entire claim will be paid
irrespective of your sum assured.
So you get this benefit in Limitless.
Parenthood Rider This is your maternity
rider that covers your delivery costs
after 2 years up to ₹2 lakh.  Now let's
talk about the riders.  The
first one in Aditya Barla Plus is the Chronic Care Rider.
He covers your A B C D Plus conditions from day one.
Reducing the Room
Category.  So there is a room modifier rider where
you can reduce your premium.  If
you agree to give me a single room
or a twin sharing room, then
you can also choose the room modification rider.
This is optional.  Then there is deductible.
Deductible is also available in HDFC and Optima Secure.
Deductible is also available here.  Deductible
reduces your premium.  So
you pay a small initial amount.   The
insurance company pays on top of that.
Then there is the air ambulance.
You can add a domestic air ambulance rider if
you want.  You can add a rider for tele consultation
if you need it.  Then there is your
DM Durable Medical Expenses.
You can get this covered as well.  And some more riders
are also available in Aditya Birla which you
can see on the screen.  Now let's talk about
discounts.
What discounts are available in the policy?  The first discount is the
multi-tenure discount.  In HDFC Ergo
Optima Secure, if you take a two-year or three-year
policy together, then some
discount is available which is 7.5% on the
second year and 10% on the third year.  There
is a loyalty discount.  If you are an existing HDFC
Ergo customer, you
can also avail a discount of 2.5%.  Aditya Birla Activ has a
long term tenure discount of 7.5%
on the second year and 10% on the third year.  And also
a discount which
we talked about health returns.  If you live a healthy and
active lifestyle, you
can avail this discount.  And this is up to 100%.
Now we will talk about the premiums and what
these policies actually cost.
First let's talk about family of
three here.  The age of the family is 35 for the father,
32 for the mother and 3 years for the child and the
premium taken for Zone One is ₹1 lakh.  The
premium for HDFC Optima Secure is ₹31,400.
Aitya Birla Activ Max is priced at ₹1,522.
Now I would like to tell you one more thing here.
We have not given the calculation of Vital premium
because Vital is available only if there is a pre-existing
chronic condition.  A B C D Plus
condition is necessary to take Vital Plan.
Otherwise vital plan is not available.
So I have not calculated that premium
because we have not considered any chronic condition here.  I have
not assumed.
So this was all from our side by side comparison
between HDFC Arbo Optima Secure and
Aditya Birla Active One plans.  I am
sure that all your doubts regarding these two
plans would have been cleared.
You can share this with your friends and
family if they are looking at this comparison
and don't forget to do your due diligence
before buying any policy.  You may reach
out to our team
on the given numbers for any assistance
regarding the policy.  Quick reminder before we go,
if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, please do so.
So that
you get the right in at the right time.  See you
in the next video.  Till then stay safe.
Take care.  Told.